<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Xit0]]></title>
  <link href="http://xit0.org/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://xit0.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-11T01:34:21+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://xit0.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Irshad Pananilath]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How i cleaned my Blackberry's trackball]]></title>
    <link href="http://xit0.org/2009/08/how-i-cleaned-my-blackberrys-trackball/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-04T21:20:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://xit0.org/2009/08/how-i-cleaned-my-blackberrys-trackball</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today morning, I woke up to realize that my blackberry's trackball didn't
register scrolls to the left. It would roll to the left but, won't let me move
to select any of the applications. After googling for some time, came upon this
very useful guide @
<a href="http://www.blackberryinsight.com/2007/06/13/how-to-clean-your-blackberrys-trackball">BlackBerryInsight</a> on cleaning the blackberry's trackball.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Had to remove the trackball fixture and take it apart to clean it. After putting everything together, it worked like a charm.</p>

<p><strong>P.S</strong>: Take pictures if you are disassembling the trackball fixture. Otherwise putting everything back together can be pretty confusing.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/<em>1UAzLLUZnSw/Snhhf8sNcfI/AAAAAAAAAlw/z-07keUFg1s/s1600/blackberry_trackball.jpg">
<img class="center" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/</em>1UAzLLUZnSw/SnhhgEXZLgI/AAAAAAAAAmA/K1GaCE9-c_o/s1600/blackberry_trackball_ball.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PageFile not getting created @ the specified location]]></title>
    <link href="http://xit0.org/2006/12/windows-pagefile-not-getting-created/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-14T17:35:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://xit0.org/2006/12/windows-pagefile-not-getting-created</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was no free space left on my windows installation drive [C:] . So I decided to migrate the page file from C: drive to D: drive.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I opened up the Virtual Memory settings in the My Computer properties page and changed the page file location from C: to D:, setting a minimum size of 1000MB and a maximum size of 1024MB. Then i restarted my PC. But windows popped up an error saying that there was no page file and a page file will be created temporarily. It got created on the C: drive itself. All the registry settings pointed to the new location and the size was also correct. But still the page file never got created on the D: drive.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_1UAzLLUZnSw/RYFDho61kuI/AAAAAAAAAAM/eT7nD1GcSW4/s1600/D.Drive.jpg"></p>

<p>I did eventually find the problem. The D: drive did not have permissions for SYSTEM group. Adding this group to the security list for D: drive with full permissions did the trick. On the next restart, windows created a new page file on D: drive. I deleted the old one from C: drive. It freed up 1.5GB of space.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
