<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | Xit0]]></title>
  <link href="http://pmirshad.github.com/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pmirshad.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-10T23:12:47+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://pmirshad.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Irshad Pananilath]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Should I Care]]></title>
    <link href="http://pmirshad.github.com/2008/04/why-should-i-care/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-19T15:11:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pmirshad.github.com/2008/04/why-should-i-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Was there something more I could have done?<br/>Or was I not meant to be the one?<br/>Where’s the life I thought we would share?<br/>And should I care?</p></p><p><p>And will someone else get more of you?<br/>Will she go to sleep more sure of you?<br/>Will she wake up knowing you’re still there?<br/>And why should I care?</p></p><p><p>There’s always one to turn and walk away<br/>And one who just wants to stay<br/>But who said that love is always fair?<br/>And why should I care?</p></p><p><p>Should I leave you alone here in the dark?<br/>Holding my broken heart<br/>While a promise still hangs in the air<br/>Why should I care?</p><footer><strong>Diana Krall</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0139668/soundtrack'>True Crime</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Taxi Driver Taught Me An MBA Lesson]]></title>
    <link href="http://pmirshad.github.com/2006/12/taxi-driver-taught-me-mba-lesson/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-13T16:17:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pmirshad.github.com/2006/12/taxi-driver-taught-me-mba-lesson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Got this on a mailing list... A really nice one.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>I needed to go from Xujiahui to the airport, so I hurriedly concluded a meeting<br/>and I was looking for a taxi in front of the Meiluo building. A taxi driver saw<br/>me and very professionally came in a straight line and stopped right in front of<br/>me. Thus followed the story that astonished me greatly as if I had attended a<br/>lively MBA course. In order to faithfully preserve the intent of the taxi<br/>driver, I have tried to reproduce his original words according to my memory.</p></p><p><!--more--></p><p><br/><p>“Where do you want to go? Good, the airport. At Xujiahui, I loved to get<br/>business in front of the Meiluo building. Over here, I only work two places:<br/>Meiluo building and Junyao building. Did you know? Before I picked you up, I<br/>circled around Meiluo building twice before I saw you! People who come out of<br/>office building are definitely not going to some place nearby …”<br/>“Oh? You have a method!” I agreed.<br/>“A taxi driver must also have scientific methods,” he said. I was surprised and<br/>I got curious: “What scientific methods?”<br/>“I have to know statistics. I have made detailed calculations. Let me tell you.<br/>I operate the car 17 hours a day, and my hourly cost is 34.5 RMB …”<br/>“How did you arrive at that?” I asked<br/>“You calculate. I have to pay 380 RMB to the company each day for the car. The<br/>gas is about 210 RMB. I work 17 hours per day. On an hourly basis, the fixed<br/>cost is the 22 RMB that I give to the taxi company and an average of 12.5 RMB<br/>per hour in gasoline expenses. Isn’t that 34.5 RMB?” I was a bit surprised. I<br/>have taken taxis for ten years, but this is the first time that a taxi driver<br/>has calculated the costs this way. Previously, the taxi drivers all tell me that<br/>the cost per kilometer was 0.3 RMB in addition to the total company fee.</p></p><p><p>“Costs should not be calculated on a per-kilometer basis. It should be<br/>calculated on an hourly basis. You see, each meter has a ‘review’ function<br/>through which you can see the details of the day. I have done a data analysis.<br/>The averarge time gap between customers is seven minutes. If I started counting<br/>the costs when someone gets in, it is 10 RMB for about 10 minutes. That means<br/>each 10 RMB customer takes 17 minutes of time, which costs 9.8 RMB (=34.5 x 17 /<br/>60). This is not making money! If we say that customers who want to go to<br/>Pudong, Hangzhou or Qingpu are like meals, then a 10 RMB customer is not even a<br/>bite of food. You can only say that this is just a sprinkle of MSG.”</p></p><p><p>Great! This driver did not sound like a taxi driver. He seemed more like an<br/>accountant. “So what you do then?” I was even more interested and I continued my<br/>questioning. It looked like I was going to learn something new on the way to the<br/>airport.</p></p><p><p>“You must not let the customer lead you all over the place. You decide what you<br/>want to do based upon the location, time and customer.” I was very surprised,<br/>but this sounded significant. “Someone said that the taxi driving is a<br/>profession that depends on luck. I don’t think so. You have to stand in the<br/>position of the customer and consider things from the customer’s perspective.”<br/>This sounded very professional, and very much like many business management<br/>teachers who say “put yourself in others’ shoes.”</p></p><p><p>“Let me give you an example. You are at the entrance to a hospital. There is<br/>someone holding some medicine and there is someone else holding a wash basin.<br/>Which person will you pick up?” I thought about it and I said that I didn’t<br/>know.<br/>“You take the one with the wash basin. If you have a minor complaint that you<br/>want to be examined and to get some medicine, you don’t usually go to a faraway<br/>hospital. Anyone who is carrying a wash basin has just been discharged from the<br/>hospital. When people enter the hospital, some of them die. Today, someone on<br/>the second floor dies. Tomorrow, someone on the third floor dies. Those who make<br/>it out of the hospital usually have a feeling of having been given a second life<br/>and they recognize the meaning of life again – health is the most important<br/>thing. So on that day, that person told me, “Go … go to Qingpu.” He did not even<br/>blink. Would you say that he wanted to take a taxi to People’s Plaza to transfer<br/>to the Qingpu line subway? Absolutely not!”</p></p><p><p>I began to admire him.</p></p><p><p>“Let me give you another example. That day at People’s Plaza, three people were<br/>waving at me. One was a young woman who had just finished shopping and was<br/>holding some small bags. Another was a young couple who were out for a stroll.<br/>The third one was a man who wore a silk shirt and a down jacket and holding a<br/>notebook computer bag. I spent three seconds looking at each person and I<br/>stopped in front of the man without hesitation. When the man got in, he said:<br/>‘Yannan Elevated Highway. South North Elevated Highway …’ Before even finishing,<br/>he could not help but ask, ‘Why did you stop in front of me without hesitating?<br/>There were two people in front. They wanted to get on as well. I was too<br/>embarrassed to fight with them.’ I replied, ‘It is around noon and just a dozen<br/>or so minutes before one o’clock. That young woman must have slipped out at noon<br/>to buy something and I guess that her company must be nearby. That couple are<br/>tourists because they are not holding anything and they are not going to travel<br/>far. You are going out on business. You are holding a notebook computer bag, so<br/>I can tell that this is business. If you are going out at this time, I guess<br/>that it would not be too close.’ The man said, ‘You are right. I’m going to<br/>Baoshan.’”</p></p><p><p>“Are those people wearing pajamas in front of supermarkets or subway stations<br/>going to travel far? Are they going to the airport? The airport is not going to<br/>let them enter.”<br/>That makes sense! I was liking this more and more.</p></p><p><p>“Many drivers complain that business is tough and the price of gas has gone up.<br/>They are trying to pin the cause down on other people. If you keep pinning the<br/>cause on other people, you will never get any better. You must look at yourself<br/>to see where the problem is.” This sounds very familiar. It seems like “If you<br/>cannot change the world, then you should change yourself” or perhaps a pirated<br/>copy of Steven Corey’s “Circles of Influence and Concern.” “One time, on Nandan<br/>Road, someone flagged me down and wanted to go to Tianlin. Later on, someone<br/>else flagged me down on Nandan Road and he also wanted to go to Tianlin. So I<br/>asked, ‘How come all you people who come out on Nandan Road want to go to<br/>Tianlin?’ He said, ‘There is a public bus depot at Nandan Road. We all take the<br/>public bus from Pudong to there, and then we take the taxi to Tianlin. So I<br/>understood. For example, you look at the road that we just passed. There are no<br/>offices, no hotels, nothing. Just a public bus station. Those people who flag<br/>down taxis there are mostly people who just got off the public bus, and they<br/>look for the shortest road for a taxi. People who flag down taxis here will<br/>usually ride not more than 15 RMB.”</p></p><p><p>“Therefore, I say that the attitude determines everything!” I have heard dozens<br/>of company CEO’s say that, but this was the first time that I heard a taxi<br/>driver say that.</p></p><p><p>“We need to use scientific methods and statistics to conduct business. Those<br/>people who wait at the subway exits every day for business will never make<br/>money. How are you going to provide for your wife and kids at 500 RMB a month?<br/>This is murder? This is slowly murdering your whole family. You must arm<br/>yourself with knowledge. You have to learn knowledge to become a smart person. A<br/>smart person learns knowledge in order to become a very smart person. A very<br/>smart person learns knowledge in order to become a genius.”</p></p><p><p>“One time, a person wanted a taxi in order to get to the train station. I asked<br/>him how he wanted to go. He told me how to get there. I said that was slow. I<br/>said to get on the elevated highway and go this other way. He said that it was a<br/>longer way. I said, ‘No problem. You have experience because you go that way<br/>frequently. It costs you 50 RMB. If you go my way, I will turn off the meter<br/>when it reaches 50 RMB. You can just pay me 50 RMB. Anything more is mine. If<br/>you go your way, it will take 50 minutes. If I go my way, it will take 25<br/>minutes.’ So in the end, we went my way. We traveled an additional four<br/>kilometers but 25 minutes quicker. I accepted only 50 RMB. The customer was very<br/>delighted for saving about 10 RMB. This extra four kilometers cost me just over<br/>1 RMB in gas. So I have swapped 1 RMB for 25 extra minutes of my time. As I just<br/>said, my hourly cost is 34.5 RMB. It was quite worthwhile for me!”</p></p><p><p>“In a public taxi company, an ordinary driver takes three to four thousand RMB<br/>home per month. The good driver can get around five thousand. The top driver can<br/>get seven thousand RMB. Out of the 20,000 drivers, there are about two to three<br/>who can make more than 8,000 RMB a month. I am one of those two or three.<br/>Furthermore, it is very stable without too much fluctuation.”</p></p><p><p>Great! By this point, I admired this taxi driver more and more.<br/>“I often say that I am a happy driver. Some people say, ‘That’s because you earn<br/>a lot of money. Of course, you must be happy.’ I tell them, ‘You are wrong. This<br/>is because I have a happy and active mind, and that is why I make a lot of<br/>money.’”<br/>What a wonderful way to put it!</p></p><p><p>“You have to appreciate the beauty that your work brings. Stuck in a traffic jam<br/>at People’s Plaza, many drivers complain, ‘Oh, there’s a traffic jam again! What<br/>rotten luck!’ You must not be like that. You should try to experience the beauty<br/>of the city. There are many pretty girls passing by. There are many tall modern<br/>buildings; although you cannot afford them, you can still enjoy them with an<br/>appreciative look. While driving to the airport, you can look at the greenery on<br/>both sides. In the winter, it is white. How beautiful! Look at the meter – it is<br/>more than 100 RMB. That is even more beautiful! Each job has its own beauty. We<br/>need to learn how to experience that beauty in our work.”</p></p><p><p>“Ten years ago, I was a general instructor at Johnson’s. Eight years ago, I had<br/>been the department manager for three different departments. I quit because<br/>there was no point in making three or five thousand a month. I decided to become<br/>a taxi driver. I want to be a happy driver. Ha ha ha …”</p></p><p><p>When we arrived at the airport, I gave him my business card and said, “Are you<br/>interested in coming this Friday to my office and explain to the Microsoft<br/>workers about how you operate your taxi? You can treat it as if your meter is<br/>running at 60 kilometers per hour. I will pay you for the time that you talk to<br/>us. Give me a call.”</p></p><p><p>Then I began to write down his lively MBA lecture on the airplane.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
